Gary B. Genett

Seattle, WA 98101 • 206-391-6606 • me@garybgenett.net • linkedin.com/in/gary-b-genett

Senior Technical Project Manager

Highly accomplished professional with over 20 years of measured success in project and program management for complex technical industries.

Goal-focused professional with 20+ years' success driving all aspects of product ownership, project management, and organizational change to cultivate growth within pressurized environments. Strong ability to build and lead teams that meet and exceed established goals and expectations. Highly adept at developing and implementing controls, processes, and best practices that enhance operational efficiency and mitigate risks. Well-versed in mergers and acquisitions, and technically proficient with cloud architecture and automation. Demonstrated ability to guide full product and project management lifecycle, from scope definition and initial planning to final delivery, to ensure on-time, on-budget, and on-target results.

Areas of Expertise

- Strategic Planning
- Project Management
- Product Strategy
- Change Management •
- Cross-functional Collaboration Stakeholder Engagement
- Program Management
- Building & Leading Teams
- Clound Migrations & Operations

Professional Experience

Highspot – Seattle, WA

Senior Technical Project Manager, April 2020 - April 2021

Pivotal role on the Content Integration, Management and Consumption teams, operating at the confluence of Product Management, Engineering, Design, and Customer Service. Drove integrations with third-party content management and creation systems like Google Drive, Sharepoint and Dropbox, enabling customers to import and organize their vast content libraries. Provided a variety of compelling data-driven customer experiences, managing the complete lifecycle of sales collateral. Developed hybrid Agile models to deliver SaaS products and technologies, applying and adapting processes commensurate with the company's strategic objectives, size and challenges. Worked closely with Product Management and Engineering to understand new features and product enhancements, ensuring that they were effectively documented and communicated, thoughtfully implemented, and thoroughly tested. Collaborated with Product Management, Engineering, Design and QA to develop release plans and track progress to success. Created development processes and tools to meet the scaling organization's needs and create predictable results.

- Grew the initial team through two organizational restructures, including dividing the group into 4 teams focused on different SaaS disciplines
- Authored multiple documents and developed custom Jira configurations, establishing processes which operationalized independent development teams with individual needs, increasing feature delivery by 400% over the course of just 6 months
- Delivered 4 frontend and 3 backend integrations with Salesforce, Quip, HigherLogic, Widen, and OpenText, driving new business with Salesforce, Facebook, Fortinet and Gojo
- Secured recurring \$2M Salesforce deal through delivery of critical required product integration advancements over 4 releases

Alaska Airlines – Seattle, WA

Senior Technical Project Manager, June 2019 - December 2019

Established design patterns for new and existing document types to develop a usable and maintainable library of all resources needed for executive, management, developer, and support audiences. Collaborated cross-functionally to gather and comprehend requirements and define clear scope. Developed document creation and management

processes for company use for foreseeable future, to facilitate migration from on-premises to Azure cloud-based model. Contributed to project scoping and planning, documentation, systems maintenance and downtime planning, and continuous improvement. Prevented disruptions to project progress by identifying and escalating risks well in advance.

- As a part of a \$40M integration program, pioneered a centralized documentation management system and ongoing maintenance processes aimed at helping Alaska Airlines become the first airline to succeed in pulling off FCC certification of full M&E system alignment post-merger with Virgin America
- Strengthened controls and overall quality of outcomes by creating and implementing best practices to ensure smooth transition to cloud-based DevOps model

Enviro-Master – Seattle, WA

President, October 2016 - January 2019

Leveraged strong leadership abilities and strategic thinking to lead a high-performing team to deliver all daily operations with attention-to-detail, efficiency, and excellence.

- Achieved a high level of customer satisfaction, directing nearly 100 sites across the Puget Sound region
- Directly doubled sales by increasing sites by 50%, resulting in an additional \$100K in revenue
- Reduced operational budget to optimize profitability, following the acquisition of failing Swisher business

F5 Networks - Seattle, WA

Intentionally performed 5 cross-functional positions over 12 years, from 2004 to 2016, spanning the full product lifecycle through market analysis, business strategy, product management, customer requirements, architecture, design, program management, product development, release, go-to-market, competitive analysis, pre-sales, close-of-deal, implementation, deployment, and migration, with support and consulting through the entire process.

Senior Product Management Engineer, January 2015 - October 2016

Guided the end-to-end product management lifecycle to completion within budget constraints and deadline. Demonstrated ownership and effective advocacy to the executive team to achieve a high-standard of support and fulfil budget goals. Leveraged external and internal relationships, influence, and expertise to direct product strategy and roadmap to accomplish delivery targets.

- Built an integral new cloud/orchestration team to ensure smooth operations and optimal productivity amid evolving organizational dynamics
- Established and drove a new vision for automation, integrating all existing technologies into a unified suite across 5 disparate teams with different knowledge domains, technology areas and development models
- Remained at the forefront of changing market trends and anticipated customer needs to develop direction

New Product Introduction Engineer, September 2009 - December 2014

Guaranteed a high standard of preparation and readiness across sales and services organizations ahead of new product and service releases. Ensured clear communication channels and optimal operational efficiency as a liaison between the company's major departments, including marketing, development, services, and sales functions. Closed integral deals and optimized retention by performing customer visits with account teams as corporate representative.

- Spearheaded the effective milestone release of 5 innovative technologies and deep product rewrite
- Steered the internal homegrown heuristics tool to pre-analyze customer diagnostic files for the support team through initial stages to customer-facing product

Education

Programming Course, University of Washington

Programming Courses, Seattle Central College